

# **Cristian Casallas**

# Fullstack Web Developer (FE heavy)

LinkedIn: Cricadev

Email: cristiancasallas998@gmail.com

GitHub: GitHub/Cricadev Website: Cricadev.com

#### Summary

I believe in harnessing the power of technology to make a meaningful difference in people's lives. With 3 years in the web development sphere, including a significant role as a Web Developer Specialist at Medallia, my journey is fueled by an insatiable curiosity and a relentless drive to never stop learning.

I approach challenges with a risktaking and innovative mindset, always looking for creative solutions. My ambition is matched only by my determination to achieve excellence in every project. Enthusiastic by nature, I bring valuable insights and a fresh perspective to the table.

I'm not just looking for a job; I'm on a mission to use my skills to contribute, grow, and make an impact.



Check out my portfolio,

#### **RELEVANT SKILLS**

- Vue.js
- Nuxt.js
- Node.js / Nest.js
- PHP / Laravel
- Typescript / Javascript
- Three.js / WebGL
- Blender
- Supabase / Firebase
- PrismaORM
- Vue Test Utils / Jest
- AWS
- Vuex/Pinia

#### **PROJECTS**

GOD

ANIMAL

#### AnimalGod: Pet Adoption Web Application

Enjoy it yourself: https://animalgod.cricadev.com/ Nuxt.js, Supabase, PrismaORM, Responsive Web Design

#### **Key Features:**

- Enabled animal refugees to register pets through a multi-step form.
- Created a system for clients to apply for pet adoptions and refine choices using an advanced filtering system.
- Ensured up-to-date tracking and management of pet adoption processes.



#### QuizGod: AI-Powered Quiz Platform

Enjoy it yourself https://quizgod.cricadev.com/ Vue.js, NestJS, OPEN AI API, Responsive Web Design

#### **Key Features:**

- Integrated OPEN AI API to dynamically generate quiz questions.
- Developed a real-time leaderboard to enhance user engagement and competition.
- Implemented responsive design for optimal user experience across devices.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Medallia

#### Web Developer Specialist

June 2022 - August 2023

- Develop new components and features for Medallia web properties using clean code principles.
- Improve the UX in multiple pages also created an export from the data of the CMS to an xlsx to make life easier for my manager.
- Optimize website experiences and user journeys.
- AWS S3, Vue.JS, Nuxt.JS, Prismic CMS, Node.js, PHP



#### Fullstack Nuxt Developer, Freelance, 3D Creative

January 2023 - Present

- Teaming up with a talented UI/UX designer, I develop innovative web applications tailored to the unique needs of emerging small businesses.
- Vue.js, Nuxt.js, Node.js, Three.js, WebGL, PHP, NEST.JS
- Together, we've been creating digital solutions that not only attract audiences but also drive meaningful engagement and growth.





# **Cristian Casallas**

### **Fullstack Web Developer (FE heavy)**

LinkedIn: Cricadev GitHub: GitHub/Cricadev Email: cristiancasallas998@gmail.com Website: Cricadev.com

#### **EDUCATION HISTORY**

#### Web Development Platzi

June 2020 - Present

immersing myself in web development, where I mastered native web languages including HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. I also ventured into a multitude of libraries and frameworks like SCSS, Tailwind, Vue.js, Nuxt.js, Three.js, WebGL, Blender, Node.js, PHP, Laravel. Complementing my technical prowess, I also honed my advanced English skills and cultivated key soft skills, shaping me into a well-rounded web development professional.

### Vue.js Official Certification Program Vue School & Vue Mastery

June 2022 - Present

I have devoted a significant amount of time studying a range of courses at Vue School and Vue Mastery with the aim of specializing as a Nuxt.js and Vue.js developer. My training has been comprehensive, focused on mastering best practices and advanced techniques in both technologies. I am nearing the end of this educational journey and am excited to share that I just received the official Vue.js certification, a program that has been audited and endorsed by Evan You, the creator of the technology.



# **Cristian Casallas**

### **Desarrollador Web Fullstack (Fuerte en Frontend)**

LinkedIn: Cricadev

Email: cristiancasallas998@gmail.com

GitHub: GitHub/Cricadev
Website: Cricadev.com

#### Resumen

Estoy convencido de que la tecnología tiene el poder de generar un impacto real en la vida de las personas. Con 3 años en el mundo del desarrollo web y un papel relevante como Especialista en Desarrollo Web en Medallia, mi camino ha estado marcado por una curiosidad insaciable y una incansable pasión por aprender constantemente.

Ante los retos, me caracterizo por tener un enfoque innovador y valiente, siempre en busca de soluciones creativas. Mi ambición va de la mano con mi determinación para lograr la excelencia en cada proyecto que emprendo. Siempre entusiasta, aporto una visión fresca y valiosa en cada tarea.

No estoy simplemente buscando un trabajo; mi misión es emplear mis habilidades para aportar, crecer y hacer una diferencia.



Mira mi portafolio.

#### **RELEVANT SKILLS**

- Vue.js
- Nuxt.js
- Node.js / Nest.js
- PHP / Laravel
- Typescript / Javascript
- Three.js / WebGL
- Blender
- Supabase / Firebase
- PrismaORM
- Vue Test Utils / Jest
- AWS

#### **EXPERIENCIA**

### Medallia

#### Web Developer Specialist

June 2022 - August 2023

- Desarrollar nuevos componentes y características para las propiedades web de Medallia utilizando principios de código limpio.
- Mejorar la UX en múltiples páginas, también creé una exportación de los datos del CMS a un archivo xlsx para facilitarle la vida a mi gerente.
- Optimizar las experiencias del sitio web y los recorridos de los usuarios.
- AWS S3, Vue.JS, Nuxt.JS, Prismic CMS, Node.js, React.js



#### Fullstack Nuxt Developer, Freelance

January 2023 - Present

- Trabajando en equipo con un talentoso diseñador de UI/UX, desarrollo aplicaciones web innovadoras adaptadas a las necesidades únicas de las pequeñas empresas emergentes.
- Vue.js, Nuxt.js, React.js, Node.js, Three.js, WebGL
- Juntos, hemos estado creando soluciones digitales que no solo atraen a las audiencias, sino que también impulsan un compromiso y crecimiento significativos.

#### **EDUCACIÓN**

# Web Development

#### Platzi

June 2020 - Present

Sumergiéndome en el desarrollo web, dominé los lenguajes web nativos, incluyendo HTML, CSS y JavaScript. También me aventuré en una multitud de librerias y frameworks como SCSS, Tailwind, Vue.js, Nuxt.js, Three.js, WebGL, Blender, Node.js y React.js. Complementando mi destreza técnica, también perfeccioné mis habilidades avanzadas en inglés y cultivé habilidades blandas clave, lo que me convirtió en un profesional del desarrollo web completo.

# Vue.js Official Certification Program Vue School & Vue Mastery

June 2022 - Present

He dedicado una cantidad significativa de tiempo estudiando una variedad de cursos en Vue School y Vue Mastery con el objetivo de especializarme como desarrollador de Nuxt.js y Vue.js. Mi formación ha sido integral, centrada en dominar las mejores prácticas y técnicas avanzadas en ambas tecnologías. Estoy cerca del final de este viaje educativo y estoy emocionado de compartir que recibí la certificación como Vue.js developer, un programa que ha sido auditado y respaldado por Evan You, el creador de la tecnología.